5th Grade, Class 4
Kayo Hinazuki
(雛月の母)この！
≪(チャイム)
≪(雛月)お母さん｡
Mom...
(雛月の母)加代！ 何日も
どこ ほっつき歩いてんだ！
Kayo!
Where have you been
for the last few days?!
(雛月の母)この！
You...
(雛月の母)あんたたち…｡➡
You!
やっぱり
あんたたちだったのね！➡
So you were the ones behind this!
人んちの娘 隠すなんて
どういうこと!?➡
What do you think you're doing,
hiding someone else's daughter?!
余計な心配させやがって！
訴えてやるから 覚悟しな！
You made me worried about her!
Be prepared because I'm going to sue!
(佐知子)あんたさ この３日の間
一度でも 加代ちゃんのこと捜したかい？
Have you looked for Kayo at all
during the past three days?
えっ 何？
私を悪者にするつもりなの!?
What?
Are you... trying to paint me
as the bad guy?!
ふざけるな！ この！
Go to hell!
加代！ 離せ バカ！
Kayo! Let go of me, idiot!
(佐知子)余計な心配か…｡➡
Made you worried about her?
あんたが心配なのは
自分のことだけだべ？
You were only worried about yourself.
What?!
(雛月の母)何!?
ERASED
(雛月の母)くそ！
何!? 何してんの 加代！➡
離せ！
私の言うことが聞けないの!?
Dammit!
(佐知子)
雛月さん もう やめなよ｡➡
What?! What are you doing, Kayo?!
Let go! You're not gonna listen to me?!
加代ちゃんも そんな あんたの姿
見たくないっしょや｡
That's enough, Ms. Hinazuki.
(雛月の母)あんたこそ 加代の前で
私を悪者扱いしやがって！➡
Kayo doesn't want to see you like this.
人の娘 さらっといて
何様のつもりだ！
How about you?! Treating me
like a bad guy in front of Kayo!
(悟)うるせえ！
てめえが 娘を 物置に閉じ込めたり３日
いなくなっても 放っておくような親だからだ！
Who the hell do you think you are,
kidnapping someone else's daughter?!
Shut up!
What kind of parent throws
her daughter in a shed
親の苦労も責任も
分からないような がきが➡
and doesn't do anything
after she's gone for three days?!
いっちょまえの口
利くんじゃないよ！
You have no idea about the pains
and responsibilities of being a parent, brat,
(雛月)うっ！
(雛月の母)この！
≪(職員)雛月 明美さんですね？
so you shut your smart mouth!
(職員)
石狩振興局 児童相談課の者です｡
You—
You are Ms. Akemi Hinazuki?
(雛月の母)えっ？
(職員)あなたと娘の加代ちゃんのことで少しお話をさせていただきたく 伺いました｡
We're with the Ishikari Development
Bureau's Child Consultation Center.
We've come to discuss
your daughter Kayo with you.
はめやがったな…
この くそ親子！
(職員)私どもだけでは会ってくださらないかと
思いまして 少々藤沼さんに ご協力いただきまして｡
You tricked me...
Goddamn both of you!
It seemed you wouldn't agree
to meet with us,
(雛月の母)
誰が会わないなんて 言ったのよ｡
so we enlisted
Ms. Fujinuma's cooperation.
(職員)それは 失礼いたしました｡
Who ever said I wouldn't meet you?!
(八代)すみません
こんな役を お願いしてしまって｡
Please forgive my presumptuousness.
(佐知子)いいえ 八代先生｡
Sorry I asked you to do this.
私の方も あの人に 一言ありましたので
むしろ お手伝いできて 感謝しています｡
Not at all, Mr. Yashiro.
I had a few words for her too,
(雛月の母)あいつらが
うちの娘をさらった犯人だろ!?➡
so I'm actually grateful
that I could help.
早く 警察 呼びなよ！
(職員)いえまず普段のお母さんと娘さんの関係のことで
お話があります｡
They're the criminals
for abducting my daughter!
Call the cops!
(雛月の母)はっ？
No, first we need to discuss your
usual relationship with your child.
何 言ってんの!? あんた｡
私と加代の関係が
何だっていうのよ！
(職員)娘さんの加代ちゃんを
保護する必要ありと判断しました｡
What are you talking about?!
What about my relationship with Kayo?!
(雛月の母)
保護!? 保護者は 私でしょ！
We've decided that your daughter, Kayo,
needs to be taken into custody.
(職員)３日間 行方不明の娘を
捜そうともしないのは保護放棄でしょう｡
Into custody?! I'm her guardian!
(雛月の母)だってそれはそこのがきが！
You revoked your guardianship
by failing to look for your daughter
when she went missing for three days!
何で 私が
犯罪者みたいな扱いを受けるの!?
It's because of that brat over there!
(職員)まあまあ 雛月さん｡
(職員)落ち着いてください｡
Why are you treating me
like a criminal?!
(雛月の母)いいわ！
えっ？
(雛月の母)
自分から 警察に行くわよ！
All right, all right, Ms. Hinazuki.
(職員･悟)えっ？ (雛月の母)出るとこ➡
出てやろうじゃないの！ 来な！ 加代！
Please calm down.
Fine!
I'll go to the police myself!
(職員)ちょ… ちょっと｡
(職員)困ります！
They can settle this!
(職員)雛月さん！
(職員)落ち着いてください！
Come on, Kayo!
せ… 先生｡
- W-Wait, Ms. Hinazuki!
- We need to talk!
(雛月の母)来い！ 来いったら！
Please calm down!
加代！
S-Sensei...
(雛月の母)来いっつってんだろ！
≪明美｡
Come on! Come on, I said!
Kayo!
You come with me!
Akemi!
≪明美や｡
(雛月の母)お母さん？
Akemi...
Mom?
(雛月の祖母)すまんかった｡➡
あの男と無理やり別れさせてから疎遠になっとったが
お前たち二人のことはずっとずっと気にしとったよ｡
I'm sorry.
We've been estranged ever since
I made you break up with that man,
but I've been worried about you
and Kayo all this time.
(雛月の祖母)女手一つで 子供を育てる大変さは
この私が よーく知ってるよ｡
I know very well how hard it is
for a woman to raise a child on her own.
寂しかったべ…｡ つらかったべ…｡
私が助けてやるべきだったのに｡
You must have been so lonely.
It must have been hard.
I should have helped you.
(雛月の祖母)全部 お前一人に
背負わせちまったべさ｡
But I made you...
DIVORCE REGISTRATION
take all of it on by yourself.
(雛月の祖母)
皆さん 私のせいです｡➡
明美を悪く思わないでください｡
Everyone... This is my fault.
Please don't think badly of Akemi.
(雛月の母)お母さん…｡➡
お母さん…｡ お母さん！
Mom...
(雛月の母の泣き声)
Mom! Mom!
＜それは 自分への
哀れみの涙だったのだろう＞
I bet those tears were out of self-pity.
＜すがって泣く母親を持たない 加代は
そんな母を もう 見てはいなかった＞
Kayo wasn't moved either.
明美や｡
加代のことは 心配すんな｡
She wouldn't look
at her weeping mother.
私が しっかり 預かるから｡
Akemi, don't worry about Kayo.
(佐知子)私は 自分が生きるこの世界の中で
子供が一番大事だ｡
I'll take good care of her.
My child is the most precious thing
I have in this world.
あんたにも きっと
そんなときがあったっしょ｡
You must have thought
the same way at some point.
ありがとう 先生｡
(八代)いや われわれを
動かしたのは お前だ 悟｡➡
Thank you, Sensei.
悟が取った勇気ある行動の結末が
悲劇でいいはずがないだろう｡
No, you're the one
who got me in gear, Satoru.
Your heroic efforts just
couldn't end in tragedy.
加代は もう 大丈夫だ｡
俺には 父の記憶が ほとんど ないけれど
父親の言葉ってこんな感じなんだろうか？
Kayo's going to be okay now.
I hardly have any memory of my father,
but I wonder if he talked like that.
(雛月)悟 ありがとう｡
私を ここから連れ出してくれて｡
Satoru, thank you.
Thank you for getting me out of here.
(八代)さあ 行こうか｡
Well, shall we go?
(雛月)｢私だけがいない街
雛月 加代｣➡
｢今より もっと大きくなって➡
"The Town Without Me,"
by Kayo Hinazuki.
一人で どこへでも
行けるようになったら➡
遠い国へ行ってみたい｣➡
When I get bigger, big enough
to go somewhere by myself,
｢遠い島に行ってみたい｡
誰もいない島に行ってみたい｣➡
I want to go to a land that's far away.
I want to go to a faraway island.
｢つらいことも 悲しいこともない
島に行ってみたい｣
I want to go to an island
that has no people.
that has no pain or sadness.
Thank you for dinner!
Next time, I want to cook with you.
-Kayo
I want to go to an island
that has no pain or sadness.
Thank you for dinner!
Next time, I want to cook with you.
-Kayo
(雛月)｢その島で 私は
登りたいときに 木に登り➡
泳ぎたいときに 海で泳ぎ
眠りたいときに 眠る｣
On that island, I can climb
a tree when I want to climb,
swim in the sea when I want to swim,
and sleep when I want to sleep.
(雛月)｢私は 私だけがいない
街のことを考えると気持ちが 軽くなる｣
When I think about the town
without me, I feel a sense of relief.
｢遠く 遠くへ行きたい｣
I want to go far, far away.
＜ついに 俺は 加代を救った＞
＜その命を 未来へと つなげた＞
I saved Kayo at last.
＜ここから先は 加代自身が
足跡を刻んでいく＞
I fastened her life to the future.
加代の向かう未来が明るい場所であることを俺は信じる
From now on,
Kayo will make her own mark.
I have faith that the future
Kayo faces is a bright place.
Episode 9
Closure
(オサム)悟
ずっと こんなだけど大丈夫かな？
(カズ)ああ…｡ 雛月を助けたとこまでは
ヒーローなんだけどな｡
Satoru's been like this all day.
Do you think he's okay?
(ヒロミ)ねえ 悟君 大丈夫？
うん… 平気…｡
He's a hero for helping Hinazuki, but...
Hey, Satoru, are you all right?
(オサム)
全然 平気そうじゃねえべや｡
(カズ)まあ 無理ないべ｡
雛月 いなくなっちまったんだし｡
Yeah. I'm fine.
You don't look fine at all.
(ヒロミ)
うん…｡ 一件落着なんだけどね｡
Well, I can't blame him.
I mean, with Hinazuki gone...
(八代)悟｡➡ ちょっと来てくれ｡
Yeah. Although that does bring closure...
(八代)加代の母親な 数年間は
加代に近づけなくなると思う｡➡
Satoru...
Come here a minute.
STAFF ROOM
だから 加代は おばあさんと
新しい生活を始めることになる｡
About Kayo's mother...
STAFF ROOM
I don't think she'll be able to see
Kayo for a number of years.
先生 ありがとう｡
(八代)うん？ ああ いや…｡
Kayo's going to begin a new life
with her grandmother.
ううん その件じゃなくて 勇気ある行動の結末が
悲劇でいいはずがないっていう言葉…｡
Sensei, thank you.
Oh, no need to...
No, not about that.
今の僕には
とても うれしい言葉だったんだ｡
What you said, "Your heroic efforts
just couldn't end in tragedy"...
そうだな…｡
That made me really happy.
結末を代償と言い換えると 少し 下品に聞こえるかもしれないが
悟の行動は 代償を得るに ふさわしいものだったってことだ｡
Yes, well, it may have
sounded a little vulgar
if I'd said "the reward
for your heroic efforts,"
but what you did was deserving
of a reward, Satoru.
欲しかったのは
加代の笑顔だったんじゃないのか？
What did you want?
To see Kayo smile?
フッ 俺も得られた｡
ところで 悟加代はずっと お前の家にいたのか？
I wanted that, too.
違うよ｡ 隠れ家｡
隠れ家？
By the way, Satoru,
was Kayo in your house all that time?
うん｡ 泉水小ホッケー部の 使わなくなったバスに
加代を隠してた｡
No. We had a hideout.
- A hideout?
- Yes.
へえ～｡
We hid Kayo in the bus Izumi Elementary's
hockey club used to use.
来るのは お前たちみたいな
誘拐犯だけってわけか｡
そ… そう｡
A place that only kidnappers
like you guys would think to go, huh?
《笑えねえ…》
《加代がいなくなった今
残る犯人のターゲットはヒロミと中西 彩》
R-Right.
I can't really laugh...
KAYO HINAZUKI
(11 YEARS OLD)
Kayo's gone now,
KAYO HINAZUKI
(11 YEARS OLD)
《今 俺がやるべきなのは ２人を
独りぼっちにさせないこと》
AYA NAKANISHI
(11 YEARS OLD)
Kayo's gone now,
but the killer is still targeting
Hiromi and Aya Nakanishi.
AYA NAKANISHI
(11 YEARS OLD)
HIROMI SUGITA
but the killer is still targeting
Hiromi and Aya Nakanishi.
KAYO HINAZUKI
(11 YEARS OLD)
AYA NAKANISHI
HIROMI SUGITA
(11 YEARS OLD)
but the killer is still targeting
Hiromi and Aya Nakanishi.
HIROMI SUGITA
(11 YEARS OLD)
AYA NAKANISHI
KAYO HINAZUKI
(11 YEARS OLD)
I have to make sure neither one
of them are left alone.
HIROMI SUGITA
(11 YEARS OLD)
AYA NAKANISHI
KAYO HINAZUKI
(11 YEARS OLD)
《加代のときと同じだ》
クラスメートのヒロミは ともかく
隣の泉水小に通っている中西 彩は アプローチが難しいな…
It's like with Kayo.
FIGHT, WONDER GUY!
TV THEME SONG
Hiromi is my classmate,
but Aya Nakanishi goes
to Izumi Elementary next door,
ユウキさんと よく 一緒にいるという話だが
何て 声 掛ける？
so it'll be hard to approach her.
《向こうは
俺のことなんて 知りもしない》
I hear she's often with Yuuki, but
how can I start a conversation with her?
《結構 ハードル 高いぞ》
She doesn't know anything about me.
うーん…｡
(佐知子)
知らない子と仲良くなる方法？
This is a pretty high hurdle.
そんなもん ストレートに
友達になろうでいいべさ｡
A way to become friends
with someone you don't know?
《そんなんで うまく…》
そんなんで うまくいくかよって思ったべ？
Just be straightforward,
like, "Let's be friends!"
《サトリか!?》
Like that would—
加代ちゃんって子がいながら
あんたは また…｡
You're thinking,
"Like that would work," aren't you?
えっ？ 何で そんなことまで…｡
鎌 かけてみただけ｡
Did she read my mind?!
You've already got Kayo, and now...
まあ 女の子なんだけど…｡
いつも 独りぼっちなんだ｡
Why would you think I...
I just wanted to trick you
into fessing up.
悪い方に考えてるうちは
駄目だべさ｡
Well, she is a girl...
うまくいったときのことを
考えれば いいっしょや｡
but she's always alone.
You can't be so pessimistic.
当たって 砕けろだべ｡
うーん…｡
You should focus on a positive result.
Nothing ventured, nothing gained.
俺 ちょっと寄る所あるから｡
ケンヤとヒロミは
児童館に行くんだよね？
Ice Hockey Club
1988 National Champions
(ケンヤ)ああ｡
じゃあ 俺も 後で行くから｡
I have stop somewhere.
したっけ！
(ヒロミ)したっけ！
Kenya and Hiromi,
you're going to the center, right?
Yeah.
Okay, I'll meet you there later. See you!
See you!
WITH YUUKI BY THE RIVER
《塾終わりが 18時半か…》
《ヒロミを家に送って
戻ってくれば 間に合うか》
HAMANASU PRIVATE CRAM SCHOOL
GRADE COURSES
So she gets out of cram school at 6:30.
HAMANASU PRIVATE CRAM SCHOOL
GRADE COURSES
《まずは 基本的な行動パターンを
調べなきゃ》
HAMANASU PRIVATE CRAM SCHOOL
GRADE COURSES
I should be able to walk Hiromi home
and get back here in time.
HAMANASU PRIVATE CRAM SCHOOL
GRADE COURSES
First I have to investigate
her basic activity pattern.
WITH HIROMI AND KENYA
AT THE CHILDREN'S RECREATION CENTER
LEAVING HIROMI AND KENYA
＜中西 彩の一日の行動は
シンプルだった＞
CRAM SCHOOL LETS OUT
BEGIN TAILING AYA NAKANISHI AGAIN
＜もし 誘拐が起こるなら学習塾終わりの
この時間帯が 一番 可能性が高い＞
Aya Nakanishi's daily activity
schedule was simple.
If she were going to be abducted,
≪(佐知子)悟！➡
it would most likely happen
in this time slot, after cram school.
ちょうど よかった！ 手伝って！
《家まで突き止めたかったのに
このタイミングで現れんなよ》
Satoru!
Perfect timing! Help me!
何で こんな いっぺんに買うの!?
安かったから つい…｡
I wanted to make sure she got home,
so don't suddenly appear like this!
重い～…｡
Why did you buy all this in one trip?
口に出すな｡
ホントに重くなるべさ！
It was cheap, so I couldn't help myself.
黙ってても 重いって｡
It's heavy.
≪(クラクション)
(悟･佐知子)ああ？
Don't complain!
That only makes it heavier!
It's heavy even if I don't say anything.
助かったよ 先生｡
お母さん 無茶な買い物するから｡
無茶とか言うな！
アハハッ！ あっ…｡
You're a lifesaver, Sensei!
Mom binged on groceries.
Don't say I binged!
ねえ 先生はさ
何で 結婚しないの？
うわっ 唐突だな｡
Say, Sensei...
う～ん…｡ いいか？ 悟｡
Why aren't you married?
結婚ってのは
必ず 相手がいて するもんだ｡
That came out of nowhere.
相手の気持ちとか お互いのタイミングとか➡ まあ 色々…｡
Listen, Satoru...
You need to have
a partner to get married.
いや 一度 手痛い失敗をしてるから➡
慎重になり過ぎているのかもな｡
And then it depends on your
partner's feelings, mutual timing...
Well, various things... Wait...
あっ… ごめんなさい｡
I've been through a painful
experience once,
so maybe I'm proceeding
with excessive caution.
(八代)気にするな｡
別に 嫌な質問でもない｡
I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
It's not a bad question.
ホントは
別の質問するつもりだったんだ｡
(八代)
知らない女の子へのアプローチ？
Actually, I was going to ask you
something else.
うん｡
俺の方が 一方的に知ってる子｡
How to approach a girl you don't know?
そうだな～｡
僕は 慎重派だから 回りくどくなっても
まず 相手の警戒心を 解くところからだな｡
Yeah. I know about her,
but she doesn't know me.
Let's see...
I'm the cautious type, so even if it'd be
beating around the bush,
警戒を解く？
ああ｡
良く言い換えると
自分をアピールする｡
I'd start by getting her
to relax her guard.
Relax her guard?
ｽﾎﾟｰﾂが得意とか 料理が得意とか
何でも 武器にするんだ｡
Yeah. Put another way, charm her.
相手が どれかに興味を持ったとき
警戒心は 解ける｡
If you're good at sports or cooking,
whatever, use it as a weapon.
へえ…｡
あ… あまり 感心するなよ｡
When she becomes
interested in whatever it is,
僕は ストレートに感情を出すのが
得意じゃないからロジックに頼ってるだけだ｡
she lets her guard down.
Don't be so impressed.
I'm not good at expressing my
feelings directly, so I just rely on logic.
うん？
何か はみ出てるよ｡
(八代)悟！ そこは 触っちゃ…｡
あっ ご… ごめんな…｡
あっ これは…｡
Something's sticking out.
Satoru, don't touch it!
(八代)悟｡ 見てしまったね…｡
I-I'm sorr—
It's...
Satoru...
《あめ？》
You've seen it.
見られた以上
もう 隠すこともない！
お前も食って 共犯者になれ！
Candy?
Now that you've seen,
there's no sense in hiding it anymore!
３年前 たばこをやめてから代償行為としての
あめが 欠かせなくなってな｡
You have some too,
so you become equally guilty!
Since I quit smoking three years ago,
プライベートな空間では どうも
これがないと 落ち着かないんだ｡
candy has been my go-to substitute.
《へ… 変なやつ》
In private, I can't relax without it.
いただきます｡
フゥ…｡
H-He's weird...
Thank you.
(八代･悟)うん？
私にも １個 ちょうだい｡
(八代)はい｡
Give me one, too.
Here.
(ヒロミ)じゃあ 僕児童館 寄って 宿題やってくから｡
おう！
あっ 待って ヒロミ｡
Well, I'm going to the center
to do my homework.
俺も行くから｡
(ケンヤ)雛月の次は
ヒロミの保護者みたいだな｡
Okay!
Wait, Hiromi! I'll go with you!
そ… そうかな？
(ケンヤ)悟｡
ちょっと ２人で話せない？
First Hinazuki, and now it's like
you're Hiromi's guardian.
R-Really?
いいよ｡
Satoru, can I speak to you in private?
ごめん ヒロミ｡ 俺 後から行くよ｡
(ヒロミ)うん｡
Sure.
(ケンヤ)悟｡
本当は 何を考えてる？
Sorry, Hiromi. I'll catch up.
Okay.
何が何でも 雛月を助けようっていう決意を見てるから
うまくいったはずの今 お前の様子には すげえ違和感があるんだけど｡
Satoru, honestly,
what are you thinking?
I saw your determination
to save Hinazuki, and that went well,
悟｡
何かあるなら 話してくれないか？
but looking at you, I still get the sense
that something's wrong.
それこそ 飛躍し過ぎてて
うまく 話せないんだ｡
Satoru, if something's up,
will you tell me about it?
I can't really explain it.
It's too much of a leap.
俺も お前みたいに踏み出したい｡
I want to make that leap, like you.
正義の味方になりたいんだ｡
続きがあるなら
俺も連れてってくれ｡
I want to be a superhero.
If there's a "part two,"
take me with you.
ケンヤ｡ この足跡 どう思う？
大人が １人 １往復｡
Kenya, what do you think
of these footprints?
しかもさ よく見て｡
靴に
布を巻いてたんじゃないかな？
An adult's, coming and going.
(ケンヤ)滑り止めじゃないな｡
And if you look carefully...
靴底の跡を残さないためかも｡
The shoes were wrapped in cloth?
Not to keep from slipping, right?
Maybe to keep from leaving
shoe sole imprints.
リュックがなくなってる｡
あと 練炭が入ってた箱もない｡
(ケンヤ)
箱の数自体 減ってるかも｡
The backpack is gone.
And the box with the briquette
isn't here anymore either.
ちぎれたボール箱も多い｡
誰かが
中身だけ 持ち去ったんだろうね｡
I think there are fewer
boxes here overall.
And a lot of them are torn up.
(ケンヤ)悟｡ 何が言いたいんだ？
Somebody must have made off
with their contents only.
加代が ここに 一人で泊まったとき
深夜に来たっていう男のこと 覚えてる？
Satoru, what are you trying to say?
When Kayo was staying here alone,
ああ｡ 何か 物騒な感じのリュック
置いてったやつだろ？
do you remember about the man
who came here in the middle of the night?
俺は その男のことを子供を狙った
殺人犯だと思ってる｡
Yeah.
The guy who gave off a dangerous vibe
based on the stuff he left here.
(ケンヤ)悟？
いったい どういうことだか…｡
I think he's a killer
who targets children.
分かってる｡ こんな話
信じられるわけないよな｡
Satoru? I don't know
where you're getting this from...
(ヒロミ)悟君が そう考える理由は
何なの？
I know. It's unbelievable, right?
今 ここで
ちゃんと説明できる理由はない｡
Why do you think that, Satoru?
リュックの中身と練炭を見て
連続殺人犯の殺人道具の隠し場所 っていう連想をしたんだ｡
I can't explain it right now.
But when I saw the contents
of the backpack and the briquette,
こんなの むちゃくちゃな話だっていうことは➡
自分でも分かってる｡ でも 俺は そう思ってるんだ｡
it made me think this was where a serial
killer kept his murderous tools.
I know it all sounds insane.
今だから言うけど 加代のことも 親の虐待を防ぐだけじゃなくて
この殺人犯から守るために 独りぼっちにさせたくなかったんだ｡
But I believe it.
I can tell you now, with Kayo too,
I didn't want to leave her alone
just to keep her mother from abusing her,
but also to protect her from this killer.
悟…｡ 将来 小説家か
探偵にでもなるつもりかよ｡➡
Satoru, do you mean to become
a novelist or detective in the future?
その話が 飛躍してるか してないかは➡ たぶん 問題じゃない｡
俺が信じるか信じないかだ｡
I don't think the issue is whether
what you're saying is far-fetched or not.
It's whether I believe or not.
(ヒロミ)こんな家の近くまで 送ってくれなくても
大丈夫だよ｡ 僕 男だし｡
STOP
いいんだ｡
俺 こっちに 用あるから｡
I'll be fine without you walking me
all this way. I am a man.
That's all right. I have business
in the neighborhood anyway.
悟君…｡
何？
僕も 悟君のこと 信じたい｡
Satoru...
僕にできること 何でもするから
遠慮なく 言ってね｡
What?
I want to believe you, too.
もちろん！
I'll do whatever I can to help,
so don't hold back, okay?
じゃあね！
じゃあね！ したっけ～！
またね～！
Of course!
- See you!
Bye!
Later!
(ケンヤ)《悟｡ 正直 俺は➡ お前の仮説を
99％くらい まさかって思ってるよ》➡
Satoru, to be honest, I'm about 99% sure
your hypothesis is nonsense.
《でも １％は 絶対
あり得ない話じゃないって思ってる》
《うん｡ はたから見たら 起こってもいない事件を想像して
ごっこ遊びしてるだけ…》 (ケンヤ) 《ごっこ遊びで構わないさ》➡
But 1% of me says
it's not totally impossible.
Yeah. Looking at it from the outside,
it seems like I'm just wrapped up
in a game of make-believe crimes.
《ここの状況のせいも あるかもしれないけど➡ 俺 悟の
その思いみたいなものは➡ きっと 何かに たどりつくって思う》
I don't mind if it is make-believe.
Part of it may be down
to these circumstances,
but I have a strong sense your thinking
is going to lead to something.
《うん》
《悟は
俺のことを信じて 話してくれた》
(ケンヤ)《だから
俺も 悟のことを信じたいんだ》
Yeah.
You trusted me enough
to tell me about it.
(愛梨)《愛梨の信じたいは
自分のためだよ》➡
So I want to believe in you, too.
《誰かに信じてほしいの
裏返しなんだよ》
I want to believe you for my own sake.
It's the flip side to someone
saying "please believe me."
《ありがとう ケンヤ｡
ありがとう ヒロミ》
Thank you, Kenya.
《僕なら助けられたはずなのに》
Thank you, Hiromi.
《18年前 そう言って
俺は おふくろの前で泣いたっけ》
I could've saved her.
That's what I said when I was crying
in front of Mom 18 years ago?
《二度と同じ思いは したくない》
《誰も 独りぼっちにはしない》
I don't want to feel that way again.
《俺なら助けられるはずだ！》
I won't let anyone be alone!
I can save them!
親に プリント書いてもらうの
忘れるなよ！
(児童たち)は～い！
Remember to get a parent's signature!
ちょっと 一緒に来てほしい所が
あるんだけど…｡
Okay!
(ヒロミ･ケンヤ)うん｡
I want you to come
with me somewhere.
(オサム)悟！
これから アジト 行ってみない？
ごめん｡
ちょっと やることがあって｡
- Okay.
Satoru, wanna go to the hideout?
(カズ･オサム)うん？
(ケンヤ)じゃあ お先｡
したっけ｡
(カズ)おう｡
Sorry. There's something we have to do.
(オサム)したっけ｡
Then see you later.
何 こそこそ やってんだ？
あいつら｡
See you!
- Yeah!
- See you.
面白くない｡
(カズ)つけるか？
うん！ (カズ)行くぞ！ (オサム)おう！
What are they sneakin' around about?
I don't like it.
- Wanna follow 'em?
- Yeah!
- Let's go!
- All right!